When the law became corrupt, outlaws became heroes.
Lawless is a crime, drama, western film directed by John Hillcoat.
In 1931, the Bondurant brothers of Franklin County, Virginia, run a multipurpose
backwoods establishment that hides their true business — bootlegging.
Middle brother Forrest is the brain of the operation; older
Howard is the brawn, and younger Jack, the lookout.
Though the local police have taken bribes and left the brothers alone, a violent war erupts when a
sadistic lawman from Chicago arrives and tries to shut down the Bondurants operation.
Jack Bondurant, played by Shia LaBeouf.
Forrest Bondurant, played by Tom Hardy.
Floyd Banner, played by Gary Oldman.
Charlie Rakes, played by Guy Pearce.
Howard Bondurant, played by Jason Clarke.
Maggie Beauford, played by Jessica Chastain.
Lawless is a 2012 American gangster film directed by John Hillcoat.
The screenplay, by Australian singer-screenwriter Nick Cave, is based on Matt
Bondurant's historical novel The Wettest County in the World (2008).
The film stars Shia LaBeouf, Tom Hardy, Gary Oldman, Mia
Wasikowska, Jessica Chastain, Jason Clarke, and Guy Pearce.
The film is about the violent conflict between three bootlegging brothers: Forrest (Hardy), Howard (Clarke), and Jack Bondurant (LaBeouf) — and the corrupt and
ruthless lawman Charlie Rakes (Pearce), who tries to shut down the brothers' Prohibition-era moonshine business after Forrest refuses to pay him off.
The film was in development for about three years before being produced.
It screened at the 2012 Cannes Film Festival and was theatrically
released on August 29, 2012 by The Weinstein Company.
The film received positive reviews from critics and grossed
$54.4 million against a $26 million budget.
The film explores themes of corruption, based on novel or
book, prohibition era, brother, gangster.
The tone is dark and emotional.